<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag:windows,cleanup | Ashwani's Tech World - Giving back to community]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ashwani.co.in/tags/windows-cleanup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ashwani.co.in/"/>
  <updated>2019-11-15T18:51:41+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ashwani.co.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ashwani Kumar]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[aryan.ashwani@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reclaim that important diskspace with New Windows Update Cleanup]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ashwani.co.in/blog/2013-10-14/reclaim-that-important-diskspace-with-new-windows-update-cleanup/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-14T08:35:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ashwani.co.in/blog/2013-10-14/reclaim-that-important-diskspace-with-new-windows-update-cleanup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yippee !</p>

<p>Finally Microsoft has released a very important update package.</p>

<p>Remember, how we used to despise the windows updates and security patches eating up our diskspace. And many a times, we even used to skip
the update with the feeling of satisfaction (just saved a lot of diskspace) <!--more--> and dissatisfaction (what if it included a critical patch).</p>

<p>Well, Not anymore! We don't have to be in dilemma anymore. Since, Microsoft has released a very important update this time, with which we can cleanup the
otherwise outdated windows update files.</p>

<p>This release is for Windows 7 SP1 machines, KB <a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/2852386">2852386</a> adds the ability to cleanup all the obsolete updates in the WinSxS folder.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Windows Updates can be terrible space hogs. Windows saves every security update and hotfix—even if<br/>they are superseded by new updates—in the WinSxS directory. You cannot just manually delete everything in that folder,because some files are needed just in case a system file gets corrupted or you need to roll back a Windows Update. - Life Hacker</p></blockquote></p>

<p>A new  recommended update was released. It can be found <a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/2852386">Here</a>.</p>

<p><b>Note: that this is categorized as an “important” update.
This means it’s not a critical security update which means it may not be automatically installed or deployed depending on your
Windows Update settings, WSUS settings, or other 3rd party patch management software settings.</b></p>

<p>Via - <a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/askpfeplat/archive/2013/10/07/breaking-news-reduce-the-size-of-the-winsxs-directory-and-free-up-disk-space-with-a-new-update-for-windows-7-sp1-clients.aspx">Breaking News! Reduce the size of the WinSxS Directory and Free up Disk Space with a New Update for Windows 7 SP1 Clients</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
